<tool id="clip_seq" name="PIPE-CLIP">
	<description></description>
	<command interpreter="bash">pipelineV5 $input $output $shortest_match_seg_length $max_mismatch $pcr_dub $fdr_cluster $clip_type $fdr_mutation $annotate </command>
	<inputs>
		<param name="input" type="data" format="bam" label="Input Bam File"/>
     		<param name="clip_type" type="select" label="Clip Type" help="">
        		<option value="0" selected="true">HITS CLIP</option>
        		<option value="1">PAR CLIP (4SU)</option>
			<option value="2">PAR CLIP (6SG)</option>
			<option value="3">iCLIP</option>
      		</param>	
		<param name="pcr_dub" label="Remove PCR Duplicate?" type="select" help="Default - No Duplicates Removed.">
			<option value="0" selected="true">No</option>
			<option value="1">Remove by start location.</option>
			<option value="2">Remove by sequence.</option>
		</param>
		<param name="shortest_match_seg_length" type="integer" value="20" label="Shortest matched segment length"/>
		<param name="max_mismatch" type="integer" value="2" label="Maximum mismatch number " help="Since mutation is important to this pipeline, when this number is set to 0, the mismatch filter won’t work."/>
		<param name="fdr_cluster" label="FDR for determining Enriched Cluster" type="float" value="0.01" />
		<param name="fdr_mutation" type="float" value="0.01" label="FDR for determining Reliable Mutations"/>
		<param name="annotate" type="select" label="Reference Annotation" help="Select the organism to use as reference annotation.">
			<option value="mm10">mm10: Mus musculus</option>
			<option value="mm9">mm9: Mus musculus</option>
			<option value="hg19">hg19: Homo sapiens</option>
			<option value="None" selected="true">None</option>
                </param>
  	</inputs>

	<outputs>
		<data format="zip" name="output" />

	</outputs>


  	<help>

**About**

Mammalian RNA is regulated through interactions of RNA-binding proteins (RBPs) with their target transcripts. UV-crosslinking and immunoprecipitation combining high-throughput sequencing (CLIP-seq) is able to profile genome-wide RBP-binding regions accurately and efficiently. Here we present PIPECLIP, a web tool which provides a pipeline for both bioinformaticians and biologist to identify the most likely cross-linking sites from PAR-CLIP, HITS-CLIP and iCLIP sequencing data.


------


**Note**
Demo data for PIPECLIP analysis available under Shared Data(Libraries). Please import into history for sample test run. More details available in the PipeClip Galaxy Manual.


**Manual**

PipeClipGalaxyManual_

.. _PipeClipGalaxyManual: http://pipeclip.qbrc.org/static/OnlineManual.pdf



------



**Authors**


PIPE-CLIP is written by Beibei Chen and Min Soo Kim from http://qbrc.swmed.edu/



------

**Parameters**

*Input*

SAM file from any mapping tool. Make sure the SAM file contains its header, otherwise an error will occur.

*CLIP type*

 - HITS-CLIP: Deletions, insertions and substitutions will be analyzed separately.
 - PAR-CLIP (4SU): Only T->C substitution will be analyzed.
 - PAR-CLIP (6SG): Only G->A substitution will be analyzed.
 - iCLIP: The 1st nucleotide of each read will be analyzed.

*Remove PCR duplicate*

 Look for a representative reads for all the reads which have the same genomic starting location. Two methods are provided:
  - Remove by starting location: A represent read will be selected from a bunch of reads with the same start location.
  - Remove by sequence: A represent read will be selected from a bunch of reads with exactly the same sequence.

*Shortest matched segment length*

This length is the sum of perfectly matched nucleotides number and insertion number. Reads whose matched segment length less than threshold will not be included in further analysis.


*Maximum mismatch number*

Although this can be set in mapping, here we still provide this filter in case users want to try more stringent criteria than what they set in mapping.



*FDR*

There are two FDR thresholds for clusters and mutations selection respectively. Default for enriched clusters and reliable mutations is 0.05.


*Reference Annotations*

Organism for which to use as reference for annotation of mutations sites.


*Notes*

 Even if you select to remove PCR duplicates for iCLIP, the program will not do it. 


------

**Contact**

If you have any comments, suggestions, questions, bug reports, etc., feel free to contact Beibei.Chen@UTSouthwestern.edu or Mins.kim@UTSouthwestern.edu.
  	</help>
</tool>
